[
    {
      "question_id": 0,
      "question": "The ratio of width of our National flag to its length is",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "3:5"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "2:3"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "2:4"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "3:4"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 1,
      "question": "Rabindranath Tagore\"s \"Jana Gana Mana\" has been adopted as India\"s National Anthem. How many stanzas of the said song were adopted?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Only the first stanza"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "The whole song"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Third and Fourth stanza"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "First and Second stanza"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 2,
      "question": "\"Natya - Shastra\" the main source of India\"s classical dances was written by",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Nara Muni"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Bharat Muni"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Abhinav Gupt"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Tandu Muni"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 3,
      "question": "\"Dandia\" is a popular dance of",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Punjab"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Gujarat"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Tamil Nadu"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Maharashtra"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 4,
      "question": "The words \"Satyameva Jayate\" inscribed below the base plate of the emblem of India are taken from",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Rigveda"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Satpath Brahmana"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Mundak Upanishad"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Ramayana"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 5,
      "question": "Mohiniattam dance from developed originally in which state?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Tamil Nadu"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Orissa"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Kerala"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Karnataka"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 6,
      "question": "Which of the following folk dance forms is associated with Gujarat?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Nautanki"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Garba"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Kathakali"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Bhangra"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 7,
      "question": "Which of the following Akademis is responsible for fostering the development of dance, drama and music in India?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "National School of Drama"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Sangeet Akademi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Sahitya Akademi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Lalit Kala Akademi"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 8,
      "question": "The Rath Yatra at Puri is celebrated in honour of which Hindu deity",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Ram"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Jaganath"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Shiva"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Vishnu"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 9,
      "question": "The book of Parsis is",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Torah"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Bible"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Zend Avesta"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Gita"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 10,
      "question": "\"Kathakali\" is a folk dance prevalent in which state?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Karnataka"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Orissa"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Kerala"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Manipur"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 11,
      "question": "Which of the following dances is a solo dance?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Ottan Thullal"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Kuchipudi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Yakshagana"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Odissi"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 12,
      "question": "The National Anthem was first sung in the year",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "1911"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "1913"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "1936"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "1935"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 13,
      "question": "Thillana is a format of",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Kuchipudi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Odissi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Baharatanatyam"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Kathak"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 14,
      "question": "\"Madhubani\",  a style of folk paintings, is popular in which of the following states in India?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Uttar Pradesh"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Rajasthan"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Madhya Pradesh"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Bihar"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 15,
      "question": "Kathak is a classical dance of",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "North India"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Tamilnadu"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Manipur"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Kerala"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 16,
      "question": "The head quarters of Sahitya Akademi is at",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Mumbai"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Chennai"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Kolkata"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 17,
      "question": "The dance encouraged and performance from the temple of Tanjore was",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Kathakali"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Odissi"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Kathak"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Bharatanatyam"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 18,
      "question": "The last Mahakumbh of the 20th century was held at",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Nasik"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Ujjain"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Allahabad"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Haridwar"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 19,
      "question": "The National Song of India was composed by",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Rabindranath Tagore"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Bankim Chandra Chatterji"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Iqbal"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Jai Shankar Prasad"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 20,
      "question": "Who composed the famous song \"Sare Jahan SeAchha\"?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Jaidev"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Mohammad Iqbal"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Bankim Chandra Chattopadhyay"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Rabindranath Tagore"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 21,
      "question": "In which of the following festivals are boat races a special feature?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Onam"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Rongali Bihu"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Navratri"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Pongal"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 22,
      "question": "Kalchakra ceremony is associated with which of the following ceremonies?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Hinduism"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Buddhism"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Jainism"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Islam"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 23,
      "question": "Which of the following places is famous for Chikankari work, which is a traditional art of embroidery?",
      "options": [
        {
          "choice_id": 1,
          "choice": "Lucknow"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 2,
          "choice": "Hyderabad"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 3,
          "choice": "Jaipur"
        },
        {
          "choice_id": 4,
          "choice": "Mysore"
        }
      ],
      "answer": 1
    }
  ]